Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
(Father,)
(أب،)
(your lies made me suffer.)
(أكاذيبك جعلتني أعاني.)
(Turns out, what you want)
(اتضح أن هذا ما تريده)
(is just a useful pawn.)
(هو مجرد بيدق مفيد.)
(All the glory and splendor you gave me)
(كل المجد والروعة التي منحتني إياها)
(was actually exchanged with my father,)
(تم تبادلها بالفعل مع والدي)
(and the Li Army's sacrifice.)
(وتضحية جيش لي).
(In the eyes of other people,)
(في نظر الآخرين،)
(this is just a joke and a humiliation.)
(هذه مجرد مزحة وإهانة.)
(I had no choice back then.)
(لم يكن لدي خيار في ذلك الوقت.)
(I do now.)
(أفعل ذلك الآن.)
(This time, I choose)
(هذه المرة، أنا من يختار)
(to end everything on my own.)
(لإنهاء كل شيء بمفردي.)
(At the flower appreciation banquet that year,)
(في حفل تقدير الزهور في ذلك العام،)
(the descendants of Wang Sun lied and said I was a merchant's daughter.)
(كذب أحفاد وانغ سون وقالوا إنني ابنة تاجر.)
(They laughed at you for being an orphan.)
(سخروا منك لأنك يتيم.)
(We promised to be buddies forever.)
(لقد وعدنا بأن نبقى أصدقاء إلى الأبد.)
(Now, all that love has completely drifted away.)
(الآن، كل ذلك الحب قد تلاشى تماماً.)
(Wan'er,)
(وان'ر،)
(one's nobility is unrelated to one's background.)
(لا علاقة لنبل المرء بخلفيته.)
(It's only related to their choices.)
(الأمر يتعلق فقط بخياراتهم.)
(Promise me.)
(أعدني بذلك.)
(If the next life exists,)
(إذا كانت هناك حياة أخرى،)
(don't lose yourself again.)
(لا تفقد نفسك مرة أخرى.)
=The Architect=
=المهندس المعماري=
=Episode 24= (Just burn all the traitors of the Shen family)
=الحلقة 24= (فقط احرقوا جميع الخونة من عائلة شين)
Xiao Huaijin is extremely sly.
Xiao Huaijin ماكر للغاية.
He pinned all the crimes on Prince Duan.
لقد ألصق جميع الجرائم بالأمير دوان.
Even the emperor was lied to.
حتى الإمبراطور تعرض للخداع.
If we want to punish him,
إذا أردنا معاقبته،
we need irrefutable evidence.
نحن بحاجة إلى أدلة قاطعة.
There'll always be a flaw.
سيكون هناك دائمًا عيب.
We will surely find a way.
سنجد بالتأكيد طريقة.
Sister!
أخت!
Yunqi!
يونكي!
Sister,
أخت،
Father gave me something.
أعطاني أبي شيئاً.
What...
ماذا...
What did you call me?
ماذا ناديتني؟
Sister.
أخت.
You call me Sister?
هل تناديني أختي؟
You call me Sister.
تناديني أختي.
When I fell asleep that day,
عندما غفوت ذلك اليوم،
I heard
سمعت
everything you said.
كل ما قلته صحيح.
You are my sister.
أنتِ أختي.
Mother and Father are gone.
لقد رحل الأب والأم.
Sister,
أخت،
can you not
ألا يمكنك
abandon me anymore?
هل سيتخلى عني بعد الآن؟
I will never
لن أفعل ذلك أبداً
abandon you, Yunqi.
أنا أتخلى عنك، يونكي.
Yunqi,
يونكي،
did you say
هل قلت
Father gave you something?
أعطاك والدك شيئاً؟
That day,
في ذلك اليوم،
Father took me to his study.
أخذني أبي إلى مكتبه.
(Wang Yanqing, Chen Shouyu)
(وانغ يانكينج، تشن شويو)
Yunqi,
يونكي،
go and play alone.
اذهب والعب بمفردك.
I'll come and be with you later. All right?
سآتي وأكون معك لاحقاً. حسناً؟
Go.
يذهب.
I'm sure Mr. Shen purposely left this behind.
أنا متأكد من أن السيد شين ترك هذا وراءه عن قصد.
These people
هؤلاء الناس
used to serve Prince Duan.
كان يُستخدم لخدمة الأمير دوان.
They were his accomplices in selling iron ore.
كانوا شركاءه في بيع خام الحديد.
Father must have found out about Prince Duan's wrongdoing
لا بد أن الأب قد علم بأمر مخالفات الأمير دوان.
and wouldn't work with him.
ولن أعمل معه.
That was why he was framed by Prince Duan.
ولهذا السبب قام الأمير دوان بتلفيق التهمة له.
After Father knew the people of the imperial court had come for him,
بعد أن علم أبي أن رجال البلاط الإمبراطوري قد أتوا لأخذه،
he secretly hid this list
أخفى هذه القائمة سراً
in Yunqi's shirt
في قميص Yunqi
only hoping
كل ما أتمناه
for this list
لهذه القائمة
to prove the Shen family's innocence.
لإثبات براءة عائلة شين.
With this list,
مع هذه القائمة،
we will surely find evidence that proves Xiao Huaijin's crime.
سنجد بالتأكيد أدلة تثبت جريمة شياو هوايجين.
Governor, spare me!
يا سيادة الحاكم، ارحمني!
I'll admit everything!
سأعترف بكل شيء!
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
(Snow flies in June.)
(يتساقط الثلج في شهر يونيو.)
(The whole family cries out of grievance)
(تبكي العائلة بأكملها من شدة الظلم)
(like Dou E, her grievance still haunts)
(مثل دو إي، لا تزال مظالمها تطاردها)
(All of Shen family's wrongdoings) (The evil are not punished)
(جميع أخطاء عائلة شين) (الأشرار لا يُعاقبون)
(are facilitated by Prince Duan)
(يسهل الأمير دوان ذلك) (لا يُعاقب الأشرار)
(Imperial Study)
(دراسة إمبراطورية)
The Shen family's case has closed.
أُغلقت قضية عائلة شين.
What's going on with these reports?
ما الذي يحدث بخصوص هذه التقارير؟
Your Majesty, please seek justice for me.
يا صاحب الجلالة، أرجو أن تسعى لتحقيق العدالة لي.
These reports are all false accusations against Prince Duan's Residence.
هذه التقارير كلها اتهامات كاذبة ضد مقر إقامة الأمير دوان.
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
since Her Highness' tragedy...
منذ فاجعة صاحبة السمو...
What's with that?
ما هذا؟
Rumors in the streets
شائعات في الشوارع
say that she used to harm the Shen family
يقولون إنها كانت تؤذي عائلة شين
so she was punished.
لذلك عوقبت.
Darn it!
يا إلهي!
Who dares to speak nonsense?
من يجرؤ على قول الهراء؟
Arrest and question them!
ألقوا القبض عليهم واستجوبوهم!
I don't care about the rumors!
لا أهتم بالشائعات!
But I received news
لكنني تلقيت أخباراً
that Xi Yan
ذلك شي يان
sneaked into the princess's bridal chamber
تسلل إلى غرفة زفاف الأميرة
during her wedding.
خلال حفل زفافها.
What did she do?
ماذا فعلت؟
She sneaked inside.
تسللت إلى الداخل.
No one knows.
لا أحد يعلم.
Only a servant who passed by
مجرد خادم مرّ
heard their conversation.
سمعت حديثهم.
She said
قالت
Shen Changning was mentioned.
تم ذكر اسم شين تشانغنينغ.
What are you trying to say?
ماذا تحاول أن تقول؟
Just tell me.
أخبرني فقط.
I dare not
لا أجرؤ
assume before you, Your Majesty.
تفضلوا بالوقوف أمامكم، يا صاحب الجلالة.
But I'm willing to try
لكنني على استعداد للمحاولة
to see
لترى
if Xi Yan is Shen Changning.
إذا كان شي يان هو شين تشانغنينغ.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I met the Young Lady of the Shen family.
قابلت الشابة من عائلة شين.
She looks completely different from Lady Xi Yan.
إنها تبدو مختلفة تماماً عن السيدة شي يان.
There has been a face-swapping technique going around in the streets.
انتشرت في الشوارع تقنية لتبديل الوجوه .
If Xi Yan isn't Shen Changning,
إذا لم يكن شي يان هو شين تشانغنينغ،
why would she be so persistent
لماذا ستكون مثابرة إلى هذا الحد؟
about the Shen family case?
بخصوص قضية عائلة شين؟
Her Highness
صاحبة السمو
would not be forced to death.
لن يُجبروا على الموت.
Will you know immediately
هل ستعرف ذلك على الفور؟
after testing?
بعد الاختبار؟
I, Xi Yan,
أنا شي يان،
greet Your Majesty.
تحية لجلالتكم.
Shen Changning,
شين تشانغنينغ،
have you always been thinking
هل كنت تفكر دائماً؟
that the Shen family died
أن عائلة شين قد ماتت
an aggrieved death?
موتٌ مُظَلَّل؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
there are many rumors in the streets
تنتشر شائعات كثيرة في الشوارع
saying that I am the eldest daughter of the Shen family, Shen Changning.
يقولون إنني الابنة الكبرى لعائلة شين، شين تشانغنينغ.
I didn't expect the nonsense
لم أتوقع هذا الهراء
to disturb Your Majesty's peace.
لإزعاج سلام جلالتكم.
I also think
أعتقد أيضاً
it is ridiculous,
هذا أمر سخيف،
but since you appeared,
لكن منذ ظهورك،
you've been causing problems.
لقد كنت تسبب المشاكل.
Today, Lord Xiao has come up with a method
اليوم، توصل اللورد شياو إلى طريقة
to prove your innocence.
لإثبات براءتك.
The Shen family's case is closed.
تم إغلاق قضية عائلة شين.
I've also allowed
لقد سمحت أيضًا
for the traitors of the Shen family to be buried.
لدفن خونة عائلة شين .
However, some people have been calling
لكن بعض الناس كانوا يتصلون
for the case to be overturned
لإلغاء القضية
and is willing
وهو على استعداد
to be in cahoots with the traitors.
أن يكون متواطئاً مع الخونة.
Since you want to prove that you are unrelated to them,
بما أنك تريد إثبات أنك لا تربطك بهم أي صلة قرابة،
just burn
مجرد حرق
their bodies.
أجسادهم.
Bring them here.
أحضرهم إلى هنا.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
you govern with benevolence
أنت تحكم بالإحسان
and your reputation spreads all over the world.
وتنتشر سمعتك في جميع أنحاء العالم.
The Shen family has committed suicide to atone for their crimes.
انتحرت عائلة شين تكفيراً عن جرائمها.
If they can't keep their bodies whole,
إذا لم يتمكنوا من الحفاظ على سلامة أجسادهم،
I'm worried that it might ruin Your Majesty's reputation.
أخشى أن يؤدي ذلك إلى تشويه سمعة جلالتكم.
Please reconsider this, Your Majesty.
أرجو من جلالتكم إعادة النظر في هذا الأمر.
I don't need you
أنا لست بحاجة إليك
to interfere with my actions.
للتدخل في أفعالي.
Xi Yan,
شي يان،
do you not want to burn the bodies
ألا تريدون حرق الجثث؟
or go against His Majesty's orders?
أم مخالفة أوامر جلالته؟
Why don't
لماذا لا
His Majesty's guards
حراس جلالته
help you instead?
هل يمكنني مساعدتك بدلاً من ذلك؟
Don't let His Majesty misunderstand
لا تدع جلالته يسيء فهم الأمر
your innocence.
براءتك.
I'll do it myself.
سأفعل ذلك بنفسي.
(End of Episode)
(نهاية الحلقة)
Lord Pei,
اللورد باي،
this item looks familiar.
هذا المنتج يبدو مألوفاً.
Do you recognise it?
هل تعرفه؟
♪Loneliness♪
♪الوحدة♪
♪How do I cross it?♪
♪كيف أعبرها؟♪
♪Whom have I ever failed♪
♪من خذلتُ يوماً؟♪
♪Incense burns through a few sticks♪
♪يحترق البخور من خلال بضع أعواد♪
♪Can the rest of my life be redeemed?♪
هل يمكن إصلاح ما تبقى من حياتي؟
♪The flowing years pass through desolation♪
♪تمر السنين المتدفقة عبر الخراب♪
♪Unwilling to forgive past mistakes♪
♪غير راغب في مسامحة أخطاء الماضي♪
♪Blaming myself for not protecting♪
ألوم نفسي لعدم حمايتي لنفسي.
♪Our vows as I should have♪
♪عهودنا كما ينبغي أن تكون♪
♪Sorrow♪
♪حزن♪
♪Counting it carefully♪
♪أحصيها بعناية♪
♪Who stayed by my side through hardship♪
♪من بقي بجانبي في الشدائد♪
♪There will eventually be a pure land♪
♪ستكون هناك أرض طاهرة في نهاية المطاف♪
♪Where all karmic burden is cast away♪
♪حيث تُزال كل الأعباء الكارمية♪
♪Not until worldly splendor fades♪
♪لن يحدث ذلك إلا بعد أن يزول بريق الدنيا♪
♪Can one understand what cuts to the bone♪
هل يستطيع المرء أن يفهم ما يمزق العظم؟
♪At dusk, with white hair♪
♪عند الغسق، بشعر أبيض♪
♪I still cannot fathom destiny♪
♪ما زلتُ عاجزاً عن فهم القدر♪
♪After countless struggles across the waters♪
♪بعد صراعات لا حصر لها عبر المياه♪
♪At last the lotus heart awakens♪
♪أخيرًا يستيقظ قلب اللوتس♪
♪Drifting across three lifetimes♪
♪انجراف عبر ثلاثة أعمار♪
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance♪
♪فقط في انتظار نظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام♪
♪The distant mountains fade along the path home♪
تتلاشى الجبال البعيدة على طول الطريق المؤدي إلى المنزل.
♪I walk with you through morning bells and evening drums♪
♪أسير معك عبر أجراس الصباح وطبول المساء♪
♪Our story lies in the mountains♪
قصتنا تكمن في الجبال
♪Like an ink-washed immortal painting♪
♪كلوحة خالدة مغسولة بالحبر♪
♪Where blossoms fall♪
♪حيث تتساقط الأزهار♪
♪I'm glad the fragrance in our hearts stays the same♪
♪أنا سعيد لأن العطر في قلوبنا يبقى كما هو♪
♪Youth slips away♪
♪الشباب يتلاشى♪
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance♪
♪فقط في انتظار نظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام♪
♪Dreams wander back to the old road where we met♪
♪تعود الأحلام إلى الطريق القديم حيث التقينا♪
♪Watching you gently play the zither♪
♪أشاهدك وأنت تعزف على آلة الزيثارة برفق♪
♪Time rests upon the strings♪
♪الزمن يستقر على الأوتار♪
♪Waiting for someone to brew a pot of tea♪
♪أنتظر من يُعدّ لي إبريق شاي♪